Guide to the Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr. papers, 1922-2007
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- Series IV: Research Files, 385866; 142 boxes
  - Subseries IV. B. Book Files, 1940s-1990s; 386180; 69 boxes
    - Robert Kennedy and His Times, 386702
      - Civil Rights, 386747
        - Baldwin, James, 386749 (Box 493, Folder 10)
        - Education and busing, 386750 (Box 493, Folder 11)
        - Freedom riders and voter registration, 386751 (Box 493, Folder 12)
        - Housing, 386752 (Box 494, Folder 1)
        - Johnson, Lyndon, 386753 (Box 494, Folder 2)
        - Judgeships, 386754 (Box 494, Folder 3)
        - Kennedy, John F. and administration, 386755 (Box 494, Folder 4)
        - King, Martin Luther, Jr., 386756 (Box 494, Folder 5)
        - King, Martin Luther Jr., and the F.B.I., 386757 (Box 494, Folder 6)
        - King, Martin Luther, Jr.'s death, 386758 (Box 494, Folder 7)
        - Law, 386759 (Box 494, Folder 8)
        - March on Washington, 386760 (Box 494, Folder 9)
        - Mississippi, 386761 (Box 494, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous, 386762 (Box 494, Folder 11)
      - Corbin, Paul, 386763 (Box 494, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 386764
        Research photocopies
        - Beaverbrook, Max Aitken, Baron, 386765 (Box 494, Folder 13)
        - Kennedy, Robert F. and Hackett, David, 386766 (Box 495, Folder 1)
        - Kennedy, Robert F. and Kennedy family, 386767 (Box 495, Folder 2-3)
        - Kennedys and Murphy, Paul, 386768 (Box 495, Folder 4)
      - Counterinsurgency, 386769 (Box 495, Folder 5)
      - Cuba, 386770
        - Bay of Pigs, 386771 (Box 495, Folder 6)
        - General, 386772 (Box 496, Folder 1)
        - Missile crisis, 386773 (Box 496, Folder 2)
        - Prisoner exchange, 386774 (Box 496, Folder 3)
      - Death of Robert Kennedy, 386775 (Box 496, Folder 4)
      - Department of Justice, 386776 (Box 496, Folder 5)
      - Enemy Within, 386777 (Box 496, Folder 6)
      - Eulogies and tributes, 386778 (Box 496, Folder 7-8)
      - Far East, 386779 (Box 497, Folder 1)
      - Fatalism, 386780 (Box 497, Folder 2)
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 386781
        - Hoover, J. Edgar, 386782 (Box 497, Folder 3)
        - Kennedy, Robert F. file, 386783 (Box 497, Folder 4)
          Copies of FBI files on Kennedy from the early 1950s through the early 1960s
      - Foreign policy, 386784 (Box 497, Folder 5)
      - Hoffa, James, 386785 (Box 497, Folder 6-7)
      - Hoover, Herbert, 386786 (Box 497, Folder 8)
      - Johnson, Lyndon, 386787
        - Baker, Bobby, 386788 (Box 497, Folder 9)
        - Kennedy, John F., 386789 (Box 497, Folder 10)
        - Kennedy, Robert F., 386790 (Box 497, Folder 11)
        - General, 386791 (Box 497, Folder 12)
      - Journalism awards, 386792 (Box 497, Folder 13)
      - Judicial appointments, 386793 (Box 497, Folder 14)
      - Kennedy, Edward M., 386794 (Box 498, Folder 1)
      - Kennedy, Ethel, 386795 (Box 498, Folder 2)
      - Kennedy, John F., 386796
        - Death, 386797 (Box 498, Folder 3)
        - Inauguration, 386798 (Box 498, Folder 4)
        - Kennedy, Robert F., 386799 (Box 498, Folder 5)
        - Library and museum, 386800 (Box 498, Folder 6)
        - Speeches, 386801 (Box 498, Folder 7)
        - State Department, 386802 (Box 498, Folder 8)
        - Supreme Court appointments, 386803 (Box 498, Folder 9)
        - General, 386804 (Box 498, Folder 10)
      - Kennedy, Joseph P., 386805 (Box 498, Folder 11)
      - Kennedy, Rose, 386806 (Box 498, Folder 12)
      - Laing, Margaret (The Next Kennedy), 386807 (Box 498, Folder 13)
      - Landis, James, 386808 (Box 498, Folder 14)
      - Latin America, 386809 (Box 498, Folder 15-16)
      - Liberals, 386810 (Box 498, Folder 17)
      - McCarthy, Joseph, 386811 (Box 499, Folder 1)
      - McClellan committee, 386812 (Box 499, Folder 2-4)
      - McGovern, George, 386813 (Box 499, Folder 5)
      - Mafia, 386814 (Box 499, Folder 6)
      - Manchester book, 386815 (Box 499, Folder 7)
      - Mount Kennedy, 386816 (Box 499, Folder 8)
      - Navasky, Victor (Kennedy Justice), 386817 (Box 499, Folder 9)
      - New York politics, 386818 (Box 499, Folder 10-11)
      - Oral history lists, 386819 (Box 499, Folder 12)
      - Pentagon/Defense, 386820 (Box 499, Folder 13)
      - Personal, 386821
        - Athleticism and risk-taking, 386822 (Box 500, Folder 1)
        - Childhood, 386823 (Box 500, Folder 2)
        - College years, 386824 (Box 500, Folder 3)
        - Family relationships, 386825 (Box 500, Folder 4)
        - Impressions of RFK, 386826 (Box 500, Folder 5)
      - Poverty/Juvenile delinquency, 386827 (Box 500, Folder 6)
      - Russia, 386828 (Box 500, Folder 7)
      - Schlesinger handwritten notes, 386829 (Box 500, Folder 8)
      - Senate career, 386830 (Box 500, Folder 9-10)
      - Southeast Asia, 386831 (Box 500, Folder 11)
      - Speaking engagements, 386832 (Box 500, Folder 12)
      - Staff, 386833 (Box 500, Folder 13)
      - Trips, 386834
        - Africa, 1966, 386835 (Box 501, Folder 1)
        - Europe, 1967, 386836 (Box 501, Folder 2)
        - Far East, 1962; 1964, 386837 (Box 501, Folder 3)
        - Poland; Germany, 1964, 386838 (Box 501, Folder 4)
        - Russia, 1955, 386839 (Box 501, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous, 386840 (Box 501, Folder 6)
      - Vice presidential nomination, 1964, 386841 (Box 501, Folder 7)
      - Vietnam, 386842
        - Correspondence, 386843 (Box 501, Folder 8)
        - Johnson administration, 386844 (Box 501, Folder 9)
        - Kennedy administration, 386845 (Box 501, Folder 10)
        - Kennedy, Robert F., 386846 (Box 501, Folder 11)
        - McNamara, Robert, 386847 (Box 501, Folder 12)
        - Speeches and public appearances, 386848 (Box 501, Folder 13)
        - Suggested Vietnam trip, 386849 (Box 501, Folder 14)
      - Watergate, 386850 (Box 502, Folder 1)
      - Wiretapping, 386851 (Box 502, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 386852 (Box 502, Folder 3-4)
    - Age of Jackson, 386853
      - Note cards, 386854 (Box 503-505)
- Series V: Personal and Family Files, 1922-2007; 386855; 28 boxes
  This series consists primarily of the files Schlesinger maintained on personal matters, including his finances, his legal affairs, and his family. Also included are photographs, scrapbooks and other personal items retained in the course of Schlesinger's lifetime.
  The earliest material in this series dates to the 1920s, and includes elementary school work and summer camp items from Schlesinger's own childhood. His high school work at Exeter and college days at Harvard are also represented, as are his years of World War II service in the O.S.S. and O.W.I. Other personal files in this series relate to Schlesinger's parents, wives and children. Some highlights of the series include essays by the young Schlesinger, including his "History of Cambridge," commemoratives of his milestone birthday parties, and material he kept from his children's formative and young adult years. A published chronology of all Schlesinger's writings through 1984, compiled with his cooperation, is included in this series (see Box 518, Folder 1). Researchers seeking titles or dates of Schlesinger's publications should find the chronology quite useful. Most historically noteworthy of all may be the copies of Schlesinger's own file obtained under the Freedom of Information Act. The file contains the F.B.I. reports on Schlesinger's background checks by the Bureau before his government appointment in 1961, as well as other memoranda about him from the Bureau's files.
  Among the photographic highlights in this series are the pictures Schlesinger included in his autobiography; photos of Schlesinger with notable figures from Adlai Stevenson to Bill Clinton; autographed pictures of Lauren Bacall and Carol Channing; photos documenting Schlesinger's single performance in xxThe Will Rogers Folliesxx; and Schlesinger's photographs of the "Kennedy years," featuring portraits and candid shots from his time in the White House, including pictures of Schlesinger with President Kennedy.
  - Early Life, 386856
    - Childhood, 386857 (Box 506, Folder 1-2)
    - Harvard University, 386858 (Box 506, Folder 3-5)
    - Harvard University, 386859 (Box 507, Folder 1-5)
    - Juvenilia and school papers, 386860 (Box 508, Folder 1-3)
    - Philips Exeter Academy, 386861 (Box 508, Folder 4-5)
    - Play/movie viewing log, 1931-1932; 386862 (Box 508, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook, 386863 (Box 508, Folder 7)
  - Family, 386864
    - Allan, Peter, 386865 (Box 509, Folder 1)
    - Bancroft genealogy, 386866 (Box 509, Folder 2)
    - Emmet family, 386867 (Box 509, Folder 3)
    - Kinderman, Katharine Schlesinger, 386868 (Box 510-511)
    - Schlesinger, Andrew, 386869 (Box 512, Folder 1-2)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Sr., 386870 (Box 512, Folder 3-5)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Sr. and Elizabeth Bancroft, 386871 (Box 512, Folder 6)
    - Schlesinger, Christina, 386872 (Box 513, Folder 1-6)
    - Schlesinger, Elizabeth Bancroft, 386873 (Box 514, Folder 1-3)
    - Schlesinger, Hugh, 386874 (Box 514, Folder 4)
    - Schlesinger, Marian Cannon, 386875 (Box 515, Folder 1-2)
    - Schlesinger, Tom, 386876 (Box 515, Folder 3-4)
  - Financial, 386877
    - Contributions, 386878 (Box 516, Folder 1)
    - Publishing, 386879 (Box 516, Folder 2)
    - Real estate, 386880 (Box 516, Folder 3-8)
    - Schlesinger family trust, 386881 (Box 516, Folder 9)
    - Wylie, Andrew, 386882 (Box 516, Folder 10)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 386883
    - F.B.I. File Copies, 386884 (Box 517, Folder 1-4)
    - F.B.I. File Requests, 386885 (Box 517, Folder 5)
  - John F. Kennedy Presidential Library and Museum, 386886 (Box 518, Folder 1-4)
  - Legal, 386887
    - Contracts and agreements, 386888 (Box 519, Folder 1)
    - Divorce, 386889 (Box 519, Folder 2)
    - Documents, 386890 (Box 519, Folder 3)
    - Wadsworth, Charles, 386891 (Box 519, Folder 4)
    - Will, 386892 (Box 519, Folder 5-6)
    - Zinsser, Barbara, 386893 (Box 519, Folder 7)
  - Memberships and subscriptions, 1970s; 1980s; 386894 (Box 552, Folder 1-2)
  - Memorabilia, 386895
    - Congressional autographs, 1922-1929; 386896 (Box 520, Folder 1)
    - Passports, 386897 (Box 520, Folder 2)
    - Photo cards (U.S. Civil War), 386898 (Box 520, Folder 3)
    - Stevenson campaign, 386899 (Box 520, Folder 4)
    - World War II, 386900 (Box 520, Folder 5)
  - Office of Strategic Services, 386901 (Box 521, Folder 1-7)
  - Office of War Information, 386902 (Box 522, Folder 1-5)
  - Parties, 386903
    - 70th birthday, 386904 (Box 523, Folder 1-2)
    - 75th birthday, 386905 (Box 523, Folder 3-4)
    - 80th birthday, 386906 (Box 524, Folder 1-3)
    - General, 386907 (Box 524, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 386908
    - Chronological, 386909
      - 1960s, 386910; Labeled "Post-Kennedy Years" (Box 525, Folder 1)
      - 1990s-2000s, 386911 (Box 525, Folder 2-3)
    - Subject, 386912
      - 80th birthday proofs, 386913 (Box 525, Folder 4)
      - Clintons, 386914 (Box 525, Folder 5)
      - Kennedy years, 386915 (Box 526, Folder 1)
      - Kennedys, c.1995-2003; 386916 (Box 526, Folder 2)
      - Stevenson (Adlai) era, 386917 (Box 526, Folder 3)
      - Will Rogers Follies, 386918 (Box 526, Folder 4)
    - Publication Illustrations, 386919
      - Life in the 20th Century, 386920 (Box 526, Folder 5)
      - Robert Kennedy and His Times, 386921 (Box 526, Folder 6)
    - Unsorted, 386922 (Box 526, Folder 7-9)
    - Oversized, 386923 (Box 527, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbooks, 386924
    - Age of Jackson, 386925 (Box 527, Volume 1)
    - Message to the 21st Century (1984 symposium), 386926 (Box 528, Volume 1)
    - Robert F. Kennedy and His Times, 386927 (Box 528, Volume 2)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr., 386928 (Box 529, Volume 1)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Sr., 386929 (Box 529, Volume 2)
    - World War II, 386930 (Box 530, Volume 1)
  - Travel, 386931 (Box 531, Folder 1-9)
  - Miscellaneous, 386932
    - Appointment to White House, 386933 (Box 532, Folder 1)
    - Awards, 386934 (Box 532, Folder 2-3)
    - Memberships, 386935 (Box 532, Folder 4)
    - Organizations, 386936 (Box 532, Folder 5)
- Series VI: Appointment Books and Telephone Messages, 1951-2004; 386937; 19 boxes
  This series is primarily comprised of Schlesinger's annual appointment books and books of phone messages from his office. The appointment books contain daily entries detailing Schlesinger's personal and professional meetings. In later years, birthdays of family members and friends (including their years of birth) are noted on the appropriate day's entry. Schlesinger appears to have maintained the appointment books himself, and they serve as a means of reconstructing Schlesinger's days and evenings as he met with the important cultural, intellectual and political figures of his time. Most years have more than one corresponding appointment book. The phone message books were maintained by Schlesinger's secretary from 1966-1983. Entries list the caller, the time and date of the call, and any message left. In addition, the series contains a book detailing Schlesinger's periodical subscriptions in the 1970s and 1980s, and a book detailing Schlesinger's organizational memberships in the same era.
  - Appointment books, 386938
    - 1951-1953, 386939 (Box 533, Folder 1-3)
    - 1954-1957, 386940 (Box 534, Folder 1-2)
    - 1958-1963, 386941 (Box 535, Folder 1-3)
    - 1964-1969, 386942 (Box 536, Folder 1-3)
    - 1970-1973, 386943 (Box 537, Folder 1-4)
    - 1974-1978, 386944 (Box 538, Folder 1-3)
    - 1979-1981, 386945 (Box 539, Folder 1-4)
    - 1982-1986, 386946 (Box 540, Folder 1-5)
    - 1987-1992, 386947 (Box 541, Folder 1-3)
    - 1993-1998, 386948 (Box 542, Folder 1-3)
    - 1999-2004, 386949 (Box 543, Folder 1-3)
  - Telephone messages, 386950
    - 1966-1968, 386951 (Box 544, Folder 1-3)
    - 1968-1970, 386952 (Box 545, Folder 1-4)
    - 1970-1972, 386953 (Box 546, Folder 1-3)
    - 1972-1974, 386954 (Box 547, Folder 1-3)
    - 1974-1978, 386955 (Box 548, Folder 1-3)
    - 1978-1980, 386956 (Box 549, Folder 1-3)
    - 1980-1981, 386957 (Box 550, Folder 1-3)
    - 1981-1983; n.d., 386958 (Box 551, Folder 1-3)